Guide to the Andrew St. George Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original inventory, Accession 2010-M-036
  - Photographs
    - Cuba
      - Vilma Espín's Conference of Latin American Left, Mexico City, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 16)
        The Anti-Imperialist Congress held in Mexico City in 1960 was sponsored by the international Communist movement's Latin American section. This event was attended by Vilma Espín along with many of the region's leading Communist intellectuals. One caption noted that "'ALL THIS TALK BORES ME' Vilma told a friend during Mexican Anti-Imperialist Congress she'd helped [sic] organize, and this picture bears her out. Vilma, a pragmatist, saw big Congress mainly as opportunity for behind-the-scenes maneuvering, at which she proved brilliantly successful. At microphone: the chief Brazilian delegate, Deputy Secretary-General of the Communist Part of Brazil, Joao da Silva."
      - Revolutionary leaders in different settings as well as Jules Dubois, editor of the Chicago Tribune, photographed on one of two trips to Cuba, Circa 1959-1960 (Box 43, Folder 17)
        These photographs are of various revolutionary leaders. Two duplicate images of Colonel Darío Rubén de los Santos in his office, probably at the Ministry of the Interior, with another official or aide. Jules Dubois, editor of the Chicago Tribune and author of the March 1959 book, Fidel Castro: Liberator or Dictator?, is seated at a table at the elegant Zaragozana Restaurant, less than a block from Havana's Central Park, on one of his two post-1959 visits to Cuba. Fidel Castro is surrounded by soldiers and crowd next to a fire truck, apparently taken at the time of his January 1959 trip to Venezuela. Castro also appears at a reception at the Presidential Palace in the early days of 1959 and on the Cuban television show Ante la Prensa. President Osvaldo Dorticós and Prime Minister Fidel Castro are seated next to each other apparently as part of a panel or public discussion, location and date unknown. Vilma Espín (in the dark dress) is shown at a televised broadcast with a panel of women who included Loló de la Torriente Brau (on Espin's right), a longtime femenina and journalist active since the 1920s and E. Lina Milanés (See also Cuban Revolution Collection, MS 650, http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.0650, see Book VIII Print 66). Former first president of revolutionary Cuba, Manuel Urrutia, is seen examining a 1963 photograph that St. George had apparently shown him. Urrutia was in exile at the time, after having been ousted from the government when Fidel denounced him fraudulently as morally corrupt and unreliable in a televised broadcast in July of 1959.
      - Unidentified Cubans and Americans, Circa 1959-1960 (Box 43, Folder 18)
        These photographs are of unidentified Cubans and Americans in diverse settings. One image at Havana's race track was probably part of St. George's story on the American honeymooners Marvin and Phyllis Minoff who traveled to Cuba in early 1960. Here one can see various gamblers looking at a mounted board with the list of horses to bet on. (For an extensive set of photographs of this race track, see the Cuban Revolution Collection, MS 650, http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.0650 and search using the names of the honeymooners.) Other photographs show two men on the balcony of a house next to a bust of Benito Juárez; close-up image of light-eyed woman with bangs identified on the back as "American Northwestern Alumna"; people standing in front of a stage with a mural showing the Paraguayan flag and a sign reading "Fuera los Yankis" ("Yankees Get Out"); two men peering out of what appears to be a meat locker in Cuba; blonde woman sitting in audience watching a spectacle; piece of luggage with straw hat; man driving car; unknown man speaking into microphone; child sitting at a table with beer bottles; and a woman with a hair braid.
    - Latin America (Box 11)
    - Latin America (Box 12)
  - Contact sheets (Box 13)
  - Contact sheets (Box 14)
  - Contact sheets (Box 15)
  - Films and negatives (Box 16)
  - Audio materials (Box 17)
  - Audio materials (Box 18)
  - Audio materials, interview with Fidel Castro in the Sierra Maestra range, Cuba, 1958 November 6; 1 wire recording (Miniphon) (Box 42)
    - Preservation master, 1
      General note
      Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 42U)
  - Slides (Box 19)
  - Writings (Box 20)
  - Writings (Box 21)
  - Writings (Box 22)
  - Writings (Box 23)
  - Writings (Box 24)
  - Writings (Box 25)
  - Writings (Box 26)
  - Subjects
    - Che Guevara (Box 27)
    - Che Guevara (Box 28)
    - Magnum cables and other correspondence concerning Che Guevara and his diary (Box 41)
    - Cuban exiles (Box 29)
    - Cuba and Brazil (Box 30)
  - Clippings (Box 31, Box 31A)
  - Clippings (Box 32)
  - Clippings (Box 33)
  - Clippings (Box 34)
  - Magazines (Box 35)
  - Magazines (Box 36)
  - Magazines (Box 37)
  - Magazines (Box 38)
  - Magazines (Box 39)
  - Magazines (Box 40)
- Additional material, 1958-1968; Accession 2013-M-020
  This accession consists of sixteen books (numbered 6, 8-21, and one unnumbered) of contact prints by Andrew St. George documenting his travels to Cuba, New York City, Miami, Guatemala, Brazil, and Chile.
  - Contact books 6, 8-20, 1959-1963 March (Box 1, Folder 1-23)
  - Contact books 21 and unidentified, 1958-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Unidentified loose photograph, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)